export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The allocation of resources to achieve the objectives of an organization is the responsibility of",
A: "debenture holders",
B: "middle managers",
C: "senior managers",
D: "shareholders",
answer: "C. senior managers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A form of training which seeks to provide employees with work experience in all areas of an organization’s operations is job",
A: "analysis",
B: "enlargement",
C: "enrichment",
D: "rotation",
answer: "D. rotation.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. An agreement between two parties which give rise to enforceable rights and obligation is",
A: "acceptance",
B: "consideration",
C: "contract",
D: "legality",
answer: "C. contract",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Deciding which objectives are to be pursued by an organization is done during the",
A: "controlling process",
B: "directing process",
C: "organizing process",
D: "planning process",
answer: "D. planning process.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The funds contributed by the owners of a business are referred to as",
A: "debenture",
B: "equity",
C: "mortgage",
D: "profit",
answer: "A. debenture",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following business organizations is funded through taxation?",
A: "Cooperative society",
B: "Public Company",
C: "Public Corporation",
D: "Unlimited Partnership",
answer: "D. Unlimited Partnership",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. One of the features of a cooperative society is that",
A: "It is operated by the state",
B: "Its profits are shared equally",
C: "It provides for one man one vote",
D: "It sells out shares to members",
answer: "B. Its profits are shared equally",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The form of tax levied on the earning of employees is",
A: "excise duty",
B: "import duty",
C: "income tax",
D: "value added tax",
answer: "C. income tax",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The part of a computer system in which data is stored temporarily for use by the central processing unit is",
A: "input unit",
B: "output unit",
C: "Random Access Memory",
D: "Read Only Memory",
answer: "C. Random Access Memory",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A primary source of funding for labour union is",
A: "donor funding",
B: "employers contribution",
C: "government contribution",
D: "members dues",
answer: "D. members’ dues.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A contract entered into through the exchange of promises is",
A: "bilateral contract",
B: "implied contract",
C: "quasi contract",
D: "Unilateral contract",
answer: "D. Unilateral contract.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. One of the benefits of using computers in business organizations is that",
A: "they function as storage for information",
B: "huge capital is required for installation",
C: "there are many qualified personnel",
D: "the effects of virus on information is high",
answer: "A. they function as storage for information.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Inflation is undesirable because it affects the",
A: "divisibility of money",
B: "durability of money",
C: "scarcity of money",
D: "stability of money",
answer: "D. stability of money",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A facility that is offered by a bank to a current account holder is",
A: "high interest rate",
B: "withdrawal from the account is limited",
C: "payment of commission",
D: "giving an overdraft",
answer: "D. giving an overdraft",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The first step in the employee’s recruitment process is",
A: "advertisement",
B: "induction",
C: "interview",
D: "training",
answer: "A. advertisement.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The process of dividing work and assigning responsibilities is",
A: "controlling",
B: "directing",
C: "organizing",
D: "planning",
answer: "C. organizing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The principle of comparative cost advantage is applicable to",
A: "trade by barter",
B: "international trade",
C: "retail trade",
D: "wholesale trade",
answer: "B. international trade",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Effective communication is hindered by",
A: "effective planning of the. message",
B: "providing feedback",
C: "selecting an appropriate channel",
D: "using jargons",
answer: "D. using jargons",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Money as a standard of deferred payment promotes",
A: "business credibility",
B: "cost of living",
C: "credit transaction",
D: "trade discount",
answer: "C. credit transaction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The last step in decision making is",
A: "analyzing the problem",
B: "developing an alternative",
C: "identifying the problem",
D: "making a choice",
answer: "D. making a choice.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A source of capital to an entrepreneur that does not attract interest is",
A: "debenture",
B: "hire purchase",
C: "loan from bank",
D: "plough back profit",
answer: "D. plough back profit",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. An individual who serves as a middleman in the chain of distribution is",
A: "an agent",
B: "a consumer",
C: "a manufacturer",
D: "a manager",
answer: "A. an agent.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A business owned and controlled by one person is a",
A: "cooperative society",
B: "partnership",
C: "public company",
D: "sole proprietorship",
answer: "D. sole proprietorship.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The purpose of the delivery note is to",
A: "check the prices of goods",
B: "cross check the goods on arrival",
C: "show the terms of trade",
D: "inform about the dispatch of goods",
answer: "D. inform about the dispatch of goods.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Downward communication takes the form of",
A: "instructions",
B: "rumours",
C: "presentation",
D: "suggestion",
answer: "A. instructions",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The function of management which precedes all other management functions is",
A: "controlling",
B: "directing",
C: "planning",
D: "staffing",
answer: "C. planning",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A highly organized market for the purchase of securities is",
A: "a free economy",
B: "the stock exchange",
C: "a planned economy",
D: "the commercial bank",
answer: "B. the stock exchange.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A state enterprise established to provide essential services to the citizens is",
A: "cooperative society",
B: "public corporation",
C: "public limited company",
D: "sole proprietorship",
answer: "B. public corporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Re-exporting of imported goods is called",
A: "counter trade",
B: "dumping",
C: "entrepot",
D: "free-trade",
answer: "C. entrepot",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A business unit in which profits are shared on the basis of member’s patronage is a",
A: "cooperative society",
B: "partnership",
C: "private company",
D: "public limited company",
answer: "A. cooperative society",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following documents serves as evidence for receipt of goods?",
A: "Bill of exchange",
B: "Bill of lading",
C: "Certificate of origin",
D: "Consular invoice",
answer: "B. Bill of lading",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The trade relationship that exist a among number of countries is referred to as",
A: "bilateral trade",
B: "balance of trade",
C: "internal trade",
D: "multilateral trade",
answer: "D. multilateral trade",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Another name for the sender of a message is the communication process is",
A: "channel",
B: "decoder",
C: "encoder",
D: "receiver",
answer: "C. encoder",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The order which reflects the process of management is",
A: "directing controlling, organizing and planning",
B: "planning, directing, organizing and controlling",
C: "planning, organizing, directing and controlling",
D: "planning, organizing, controlling and directing",
answer: "C. planning, organizing, directing and controlling.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A convenient method of making periodic fixed payments by the bank from a customer’s account is",
A: "bank draft",
B: "certified cheque",
C: "money order",
D: "standing order",
answer: "D. standing order.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The management structure where top managers take all decisions is",
A: "centralization",
B: "decentralization",
C: "departmentalization",
D: "segmentation",
answer: "A. centralization",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The division of a market into identifiable sub-markets for the purpose of reaching target consumers is",
A: "marking mix",
B: "market segmentation",
C: "product mix",
D: "product differentiation",
answer: "B. market segmentation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. An identity given to a product which distinguishes it from other products is",
A: "branding",
B: "pricing",
C: "packing",
D: "servicing",
answer: "A. branding",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. An external source of finance to a business is",
A: "leasing",
B: "profit",
C: "running down stock",
D: "sale of fixed assets",
answer: "A. leasing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A communication process in which feedback is provided by the receiver is",
A: "diagonal communication",
B: "an informal communication",
C: "a one-way communication",
D: "a two-way communication",
answer: "D. a two-way communication",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The amount payable periodically by companies to shareholders is",
A: "commission",
B: "dividend",
C: "interest",
D: "premium",
answer: "B. dividend",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. One of the ways of controlling the supply of money is through",
A: "bank rate",
B: "customs duties",
C: "fixed deposit",
D: "trade barrier",
answer: "A. bank rate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The right to plan, direct and control the efforts of other people in an organization is",
A: "accountability",
B: "authority",
C: "delegation",
D: "responsibility",
answer: "B. authority",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Pay-As-You-Earn is an example of",
A: "fixed deduction",
B: "annual deduction",
C: "statutory deduction",
D: "valuable deduction",
answer: "C. statutory deduction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The management function of evaluating a company’s performance to see if its goals are being met is",
A: "directing",
B: "controlling",
C: "planning",
D: "staffing",
answer: "B. controlling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. A closed indent would state the",
A: "exact goods to be bought",
B: "firm whose goods should be bought",
C: "period for marketing the goods",
D: "purpose for buying the goods",
answer: "B. firm whose goods should be bought",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The document issued to a public limited company to commence business is",
A: "article of association",
B: "certificate of incorporation",
C: "certificate of trading",
D: "memorandum of association",
answer: "C. certificate of trading",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A document that contains the duties and responsibilities of a position in an organization is",
A: "description",
B: "enlargement",
C: "evaluation",
D: "specification",
answer: "A. description",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. One of the problems associated with middlemen in business is that they",
A: "buy in large quantities",
B: "grant credit to retailer",
C: "hoard goods",
D: "sell goods",
answer: "A. buy in large quantities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A neutral party that engages in settling disputes between the management of a business and the workers is referred to as",
A: "arbitrator",
B: "convener",
C: "liquidator",
D: "promoter",
answer: "A. arbitrator",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]